Guide to the Washington Office on Latin America Records, 1962-2020 and undated, bulk 1974-2005; 1962-ongoing RL.01401
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2013-0053), 39 boxes
  - Citizen Security Program, 1991-2007
    - Guatemala: Cases, 2003-2004 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Comision de la Mujer, 2007 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Consultative Group, 2002 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Consultative Group, 2003, 2 folders (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Delegations HR Women, 2005 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Fiscalia de la Mujer (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Human Rights, Death Threats, 2002 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Human Rights, Altolaguirre Notes, 2005 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Human Rights, Barn Break, 2003 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Human Rights, Campo Pagado, 2002 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Human Rights, General, 2005 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Human Rights, Meeting with Ambassador Castillo, 2005 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Human Rights, NGO Meeting with Security Cabinet, 2005 (Box 473)
    - Guatamala: Human Rights, Sign-On Letter, 2005 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: JF Notes, 2006 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: LASA, 2006 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: Miscellaneous (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: OEA, Letter, 2003 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: Peace Process, 1997 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: PNC Reports (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: Public Security (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: VAW, Hill Briefing, 2004 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: VAW, Iniciativa Para Reformar El Codigo Penal, 2002 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: VAW, PDH Petition (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: VAW, Punto Resolutivo, 2005 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: Women, CALDH Presentation, 2005 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: Women, Congressional Briefing Presentations, 2005 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: Women, DC Letter, 2006 (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: Women, Diagnostic Study (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: Women, Peralta Incident (Box 435)
    - Guatemala: Women, Strategic Meeting, 2007 (Box 435)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 435)
    - Mujeres Haciendo Incidencia, 2000 (Box 435)
    - Police: CSIS-PERF (Box 435)
    - Police: Drugs (Box 435)
    - Training: Bajo Lampa (Box 435)
    - Training: Basic Advocacy Methodology Outline (Box 435)
    - Training: Basic Manual (Box 435)
    - Training: Case Study, Solola (Box 436)
    - Training: Delegation, Convergencia de Mujeres, 2000 (Box 436)
    - Training: Escuela Mujeres, 1998 (Box 436)
    - Training: Escuela Mujeres Presentations, 2000 (Box 436)
    - Training: Honduras (Box 436)
    - Training: Honduras, Diagnostico, 2001 (Box 436)
    - Training: Manuals, Andrew McKinley, 2000 (Box 436)
    - Training: Nicaragua, Diagnostico (Box 436)
    - Training: Women, Guatemala (Box 436)
    - USA: LASA, Solola Case Study, 2001 (Box 436)
    - VAW: CHCI Fellow, Iliana Estevez (Box 436)
    - VAW: Evidentiary Consideration in Gender-Based Violence, 2007, 4 folders (Box 436)
    - VAW: House Resolution-HR100, 2007 (Box 437)
    - VAW: Senate Resolution (Box 437)
    - VAW: UNC Report (Box 437)
    - Women: Bill Project, 2006 (Box 437)
    - Women: Case, C. Velasquez, 2005-2006, 2 folders (Box 437)
    - Women: Case, M. Isabel Veliz Franco (Box 437)
    - Women: Cases, 2005-2007 (Box 437)
    - Women: Congressional Briefing, 2006 (Box 437)
    - Women: Delegation, Giovana Lemus, 2006 (Box 437)
    - Women: Fact Sheet, UNIFEM, 2006 (Box 437)
    - Women: Informe de Avance, 2006 (Box 437)
    - Women: Nicaragua (Box 437)
    - Women: Nicaragua Trip, 2006 (Box 437)
    - AV Materials, 4 VHS tapes, 2 cassette tapes, 2cds (Box 438)
  - Police Project, 1991-2003
    Contains files of Rachel Neild. The contents primarily focus on the WOLA Police Project, international police reform, and U.S.-Cuba legislation and policy. Cuba, Mexico and Central America are well-represented. Materials contain correspondence, reports, conference proceedings/papers, presentations, sign-on letters, AV materials, and general documents. Folders arranged alphabetically.
    - Arca Foundation, Correspondence (Box 439)
    - Arca Foundation, Site Visit, 2000 (Box 439)
    - Audits, 2001 (Box 439)
    - Chile: Fruhling (Box 439)
    - Chile:Santiago Summit, 1998 (Box 439)
    - Christopher Reynolds Proposal, 2001 (Box 439)
    - Costa Rica: Congressional Action, Policy Academy (Box 439)
    - Cuba: Articles (Box 439)
    - Cuba: Campaign, Church of the Brethern, 1992 (Box 439)
    - Cuba: Campaign, Mailing Lists (Box 439)
    - Cuba: Elian Gonzalez, Editorials, 2000 (Box 439)
    - Cuba: Elian Gonzalez, Hill Drop, 2000 (Box 439)
    - Cuba: Hill Meeting (Box 439)
    - Cuba: Hill Work (Box 439)
    - Cuba: Labor Report (Box 439)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Ag Conference (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Correspondence (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Iowa (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Lousiana (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Michigan (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Pilot Project (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Senate Target List (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Steering Committee, 2002 (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Terrorist List Removal (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Legislation, Travel Policy (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Pamphlets (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Planning, 2001 (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Polls (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Project Idea Meeting (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Reports, 2001 (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Sign-on Letter, Bush, 2001 (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Sign-on Letter, Clinton, 2000 (Box 440)
    - Cuba: Sign-on Letter, House and Senate, 2000 (Box 440)
    - Cuba: "Traders" (Box 440)
    - Cuba, Church State Relations, 2001 (Box 471)
      Box 471 contains the Cuba files of Geoff Thale, Sr. Associate for Cuba Policy at the time.
    - Cuba, CIP Conference, 2000 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, Congressional Record, 1999-2000 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, Misc., 2003 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, Legislation, 106th and 107th Congress, 2000-2001 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, Moakley-McGovern Correspondence, 2000 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, Moakley-McGovern Delegation, 2000, 2 folders (Box 471)
    - Cuba: Rockefeller, US-Cuba Policy post September 11, 2001 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, Sanctions, Articles, 1997-1998 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, WOLA Delegation, 2000 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, WOLA, Cuban Committee for Democracy (CCD), 1999 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, WOLA Releases, 1999-2000 (Box 471)
    - Cuba, Policy, 2001 (Box 471)
    - Department of Justice, Criminal Division, 1996 (Box 441)
    - Dominican Republic: Police Report, 2002-2003 (Box 441)
    - El Salvador: ICITAP, 2001 (Box 441)
    - FADS (Box 441)
    - FADS, Final Report, 2001 (Box 441)
    - Female Police Stations (Box 441)
    - FESPAD (Box 441)
    - FESPAD: El Salvador, 2 folders (Box 441)
    - FESPAD: El Salvador, Report, 2001 (Box 442)
    - GAO: Testimony, COPS Program, 1999 (Box 442)
    - Guatemala: FADS (Box 442)
    - Guatemala: IECCP (Box 442)
    - Guatemala: IEDADES, 2000 (Box 442)
    - Guatemala: IEPADES (Box 442)
    - Guatemala: Police Reform, Vasquez, Silvia (Box 442)
    - Haiti: NCHR, 2003 (Box 442)
    - Haiti: Justice Task Force, Overview of Judicial Reform Agenda, 1997 (Box 442)
    - Hewlett Foundation, Status Report, 2001 (Box 442)
    - Honduras: Citizen Forum, 1 of 3 folders (Box 442)
    - Honduras: Citizen Forum, 2 of 3 folders (Box 443)
    - Honduras: ICITAP (Box 443)
    - Honduras: Police Reform, Assorted Materials (Box 443)
    - ICITAP Memo, 2001 (Box 443)
    - IEPADES, 2000-2001 (Box 443)
    - LASA Panel, Neild, 2001 (Box 443)
    - LAWG: Security Issues, 1999 (Box 443)
    - Luncheon Discussion, Zalaquett, 1991 (Box 443)
    - Mexico: Conference, 2003 (Box 443)
    - Mexico: Conference, Report, 2003 (Box 443)
    - Mexico: Conference, Speakers, 2003 (Box 443)
    - Mexico: Correspondence, Mexico City Trips, 2000-2003 (Box 443)
    - Mexico: Georgetown Seminar, 2002 (Box 444)
    - Mexico: Longoria, M., 2002 (Box 444)
    - Mexico: Police Reform, 2002-2003 (Box 444)
    - Mexico: Vargas, E. (Box 444)
    - Mexico: Via Coapa, Rico, J. (Box 444)
    - Mexico, Zermeno, S. (Box 444)
    - Military Accountability Report (Box 444)
    - Neild, R.: Articles, 2001 (Box 444)
    - OFAC Travel License (Box 444)
    - Oversight Hearing: DoJ Report (Box 444)
    - Peru: Andes Seminar, 1991 (Box 444)
    - Police: Civilian Review, 1999 (Box 444)
    - Police: Congress Hearing, 1995 (Box 444)
    - Police: Costa Rica (Box 444)
    - Police: Delegation Visit, 1998, 1 of 2 folders (Box 444)
    - Police: Delegation Visit, 1998, 1 of 2 folders (Box 445)
    - Police: El Salvador, 2 folders (Box 445)
    - Police: El Salvador, Sandoval memo, 1999 (Box 445)
    - Police: FBI (Box 445)
    - Police: GAO Study, 1998-1999 (Box 445)
    - Police: Glossary (Box 445)
    - Police: Guatemala, IECCPG Report, 1 of 2 folders (Box 445)
    - Police: Guatemala, IECCPG Report, 1 of 2 folders (Box 446)
    - Police: Guatemala, MINUGUA (Box 446)
    - Police: Guatemala, Reform, 2 folders (Box 446)
    - Police: Honduras, 2 folders (Box 446)
    - Police: Human Rights Training Evaluation (Box 447)
    - Police: ICITAP and CIA (Box 447)
    - Police: ICITAP, General Background, 2 folders (Box 447)
    - Police: ICITAP, Human Dignity Course (Box 447)
    - Police: ICITAP, Scandal, 1997 (Box 447)
    - Police: INS, 1996 (Box 447)
    - Police: Internal Affairs (Box 447)
    - Police: Mexico, 2 folders (Box 447)
    - Police: Nicaragua (Box 447)
    - Police: Panama (Box 448)
    - Police: PDD71 (Box 448)
    - Police: PRODECA (Box 448)
    - Police: Report Launch, 2003 (Box 448)
    - Police: Spector Amendment (Box 448)
    - Police: Undercover Operations (Box 448)
    - Police: Use of Force (Box 448)
    - Police Project: Advisory Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 448)
    - Police Project: Assorted Publications, 2 folders (Box 448)
    - Police Project: Contacts (Box 448)
    - Police Project: Counterpart Evaluations (Box 448)
    - Police Project: Counterpart Resources (Box 448)
    - Police Project: Country Papers (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Country Papers, Authors (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Correspondence (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Gustavo Palmieri (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Mailing, Issue Packet Orders, 2 folders (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Mailing Lists (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Mailing, Order Materials (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Management (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Memos (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Methodology (Box 449)
    - Police Project: Miscellaneous (Box 450)
    - Police Project: Planning, 2000-2001 (Box 450)
    - Police Project: Police Experts (Box 450)
    - Police Project: Project Book, 1999-2001, 2 folders (Box 450)
    - Police Project: Project Calendar, 2000 (Box 450)
    - Police Project: Proposal and Workplan (Box 450)
    - Police Project: Regional Meetings, 3 folders (Box 450)
    - Police Project: Regional Meetings, Meeting Tapes (AV) (Box 451)
    - Police Project: Research Review Meeting, 2000 (Box 451)
    - Police Project: SIDA, Interim Report, 2001 (Box 451)
    - Police Project: Travel (Box 451)
    - Police Project: Update, 2000 (Box 451)
    - Police Reform Conference: Agendas, 1994 (Box 451)
    - Police Reform Conference: Conference Papers, 1994, 2 folders (Box 451)
    - Police Reform Conference: Conference Papers, Translations, 1995-1996 (Box 451)
    - Police Reform Conference: Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 451)
    - Police Reform Conference: Participant Information, 1994 (Box 451)
    - Police Reform Conference: Paul E. Transcript (Box 451)
    - Police Reform Conference: Rapporteur Report, 1994, 1 of 2 folders (Box 451)
    - Police Reform Conference: Rapporteur Report, 1994, 1 of 2 folders (Box 452)
    - Police Reform Conference: WOLA-SAIS, 2001 (Box 452)
    - Police Reform Conference: WOLA-SAIS, AV materials (Box 452)
    - Police Reform Conference: WOLA-SAIS, Mailing List, 2001 (Box 452)
    - Police Reform Conference: WOLA-SAIS, Presentations (Box 452)
    - Police Reform Conference: WOLA-SAIS, Rapporteur, 2001 (Box 452)
    - Police Reform Working Group, 1999-2000 (Box 452)
    - SoCone Trip, 1997-1998 (Box 453)
    - Suriname Letter, 1997 (Box 453)
    - Tamargo Hearing, 2001 (Box 453)
    - Tinker Foundation, Proposal, 2001 (Box 453)
    - United Nations: El Salvador (Box 453)
    - U.S.-Cuba: Policy Year End Update, 2000 (Box 453)
    - U.S. Interest Section, Havana (Box 453)
    - USIP Information (Box 453)
    - War Crimes Act, 1991 (Box 453)
    - WOLA: Pamphlets (Box 453)
    - World Development Report, Agriculture, 2008 (Box 453)
    - WOLA Publications: Public Security Reform, 2 folders (Box 453)
  - Rights and Development
    Contains files of Vicki Gass and Geoff Thale with particular emphasis on WOLA's Rights and Development program, which focuses on the relationship between human rights, economic development and US policy; foreign aid and trade policy, with a special emphasis on poverty reduction, labor rights and the rural sector in Latin America. Materials contain subject and project files, correspondence, reports, conference proceedings/papers, pamphlets and articles, presentations, and general documents. Folders arranged alphabetically.
    - Adato, Michelle. "The Impact of Progresa", 2000 (Box 454)
    - Amazon Protests, 2009, 2 folders (Box 454)
    - Amnesty International: Urgent Action, 2001-2002 (Box 454)
    - Argentina: Financial, 2001-2001 (Box 454)
    - Argentina: General, Articles and Communication, 2010 (Box 454)
    - ASONOG: Pamphlets (Box 454)
    - Assorted Articles, 2006-2010 (Box 454)
    - Assorted Pamphlets (Box 454)
    - ATPA, 2003-2004, 2 folders (Box 455)
    - Behrman, Jere R. et al., FCND Discussion Paper, 2001 (Box 455)
    - Bolivia: Afroboliviano, 2005-2007 (Box 455)
    - Brazil: Articles, 2002-2010 (Box 455)
    - Brazil: Caucus, 2002-2003 (Box 455)
    - Brazil: Elections, 2002 (Box 455)
    - Brazil: IDB, 2003 (Box 455)
    - Brazil: Lulu Articles, 2002-2003, 2 folders (Box 455)
    - Brazil: Proyecto Fome Zero (Box 456)
    - Brazil: Strategy Network, 2003 (Box 456)
    - Brazil-U.S., Assorted Material (Box 456)
    - CAFOD: Report, Gold Mining, 2006 (Box 456)
    - CAFTA: Congress, Target Lists (Box 456)
    - CAFTA: General, 2 folders (Box 456)
    - CAFTA-DR, 2005, 2 folders (Box 456)
    - CAFTA-DR: Statements, 2005 (Box 456)
    - CAFTA-DR: Update, 2009 (Box 456)
    - CAOI, 2007 (Box 457)
    - Carnegie Endowment, International Peace, 2001-2002 (Box 457)
    - Cash Transfer Programs, 2 folders (Box 457)
    - CDMA Research, 2008 (Box 457)
    - Center for Hemispheric Defense Studies, 2006-2008 (Box 457)
    - Center for Economic Policy and Research, 2002-2004 (Box 457)
    - CEPAL, 2001-2001 (Box 457)
    - Chile: Free Trade, 2002 (Box 457)
    - Central America: Gang Violence, 2005 (Box 457)
    - CICIG: Distribution (Box 457)
    - Citizen Security Initiative, 2005 (Box 457)
    - Colombia: Articles, General (Box 458)
    - Colombia: Articles, Guerrillas (Box 458)
    - Colombia: Articles, Oil, 2001-2002 (Box 458)
    - Colombia: Articles, Paramilitaries, 1999-2001 (Box 458)
    - Colombia: CRS Report, 2001 (Box 458)
    - Colombia: Drugs, 2006 (Box 458)
    - Colombia: Free Trade Agreement, 2007-2009, 3 folders (Box 458)
    - Colombia: Fumigation, 2001 (Box 459)
    - Colombia: GAO, 1999 (Box 459)
    - Colombia: Hoover Report, 2001 (Box 459)
    - Colombia: Internal Displacement, 2000-2002 (Box 459)
    - Colombia: Labor and Trade, 2008 (Box 459)
    - Colombia: National Security, 2001-2010 (Box 459)
    - Colombia: Peace Process, 2002 (Box 459)
    - Colombia: U.S. Defense Contracts, 2000 (Box 459)
    - Colombia: U.S. Policy, 1994-2001 (Box 459)
    - Colombia: Women's Delegation, 2007 (Box 459)
    - Congressional Caucuses, 2002-2003 (Box 460)
    - Counterdrug Activities, 1998-2002 (Box 460)
    - Defense Ministerial Conference, 1995-2004 (Box 460)
    - Department of Multidimensional Security (Box 460)
    - Earth Summit, Agenda 21, 1997 (Box 460)
    - Ecuador: Articles, 2002-2006 (Box 460)
    - El Salvador: General, 2001-2002 (Box 460)
    - El Salvador: ILEA, 2005 (Box 460)
    - El Salvador: Mining, 2007-2008 (Box 460)
    - FAA: Recommendations (Box 460)
    - Farm Bill: Assorted Materials, 2006-2008 (Box 460)
    - FBI: FOIA Response, 2004 (Box 460)
    - FIAN: Right to Food (Box 460)
    - Food Aid, 3 folders (Box 461)
    - Food Security (Box 461)
    - Foreign Policy Elite, Contact List (Box 461)
    - Frigo, Darci (Box 461)
    - FTAA: Assorted Articles, 2003, 2 folders (Box 461)
    - Garcia Valle, Francisco Jose, 2002 (Box 461)
    - Global Development (Box 461)
    - Global Hunger Issues,2008-2009 (Box 462)
    - Gold Mining International, 2005-2007 (Box 462)
    - Guatemala Conference, Security-Defense Integration, 2006 (Box 462)
    - Guatemala Mining, 2004-2008 (Box 462)
    - Haiti, Assorted Materials, 2004-2007 (Box 462)
    - Haiti, ICG Reports, 2004-2006 (Box 462)
    - Haiti, News Update, 2006 (Box 462)
    - Haiti, USAID, 2003-2007, 2 folders (Box 462)
    - HCA and HMA, 2005 (Box 462)
    - Hispanic Alliance for Free Trade, 2005 (Box 462)
    - H.R. 2410, 2009 (Box 463)
    - H.R. 3447, Menendez, 2003-2004 (Box 463)
    - Honduras, General Articles, 2001 (Box 463)
    - Honduras, General Communications, 2009-2010 (Box 463)
    - Honduras, Interforos, 2000 (Box 463)
    - Honduras, Mining, 2008 (Box 463)
    - Human Rights, Health, 2001-2002 (Box 463)
    - Human Rights Council of Australia (Box 463)
    - IDB, Corruption, 2002 (Box 463)
    - IDB, General, 2001-2002, 2 folders (Box 463)
    - IDB, Plan Peubla Panama (PPP) Consultation, 2002 (Box 464)
    - IFAD, Rural Poverty, 2007 (Box 464)
    - IMF and World Bank Articles, 2002 (Box 464)
    - Immigration, Assorted Materials, 2007 (Box 464)
    - Inter-American Democratic Charter, 2001 (Box 464)
    - International Farming, 2006-2007 (Box 464)
    - JIATF Presentation, 2005-2006 (Box 464)
    - Jochnick, Chris, "The Human Rights Challenge" (Box 464)
    - Koh, Harold H., Colombia Speech, 1999 (Box 464)
    - Korea, Social Programs, 2000 (Box 464)
    - Latin America, Articles, 2003-2004 (Box 464)
    - Latin America, Economic Crisis, 2009 (Box 464)
    - Latin America, President Bush, 2007 (Box 464)
    - Leogrande, William et al, "Two Wars or One?", 2000 (Box 464)
    - Mares, Carlos F, "Social Function of the Land", 2003 (Box 464)
    - Masstricht Guidelines, 1997 (Box 464)
    - Mexico, Mining, 2006-2008 (Box 464)
    - MFA Forum, 2009 (Box 464)
    - Migration, Assorted Materials, 2007 (Box 464)
    - Mining Facilities, Latin America, 2006 (Box 465)
    - Misc. Materials, 2000-2009, 2 folders (Box 465)
    - NAFTA, 2 folders (Box 465)
    - NAFTA Assessment, 2002-2004 (Box 465)
    - National Family Farms, 2002-2003 (Box 465)
    - NGOs, A Guide to Budget Work (Box 465)
    - NGOs, Reference Guide, 2002 (Box 465)
    - NGOs, United States, 2002 (Box 465)
    - Nicaragua, Election, 2001 (Box 466)
    - Notes, Congress on Trade (Box 466)
    - Organized Crime, 2005 (Box 466)
    - Oxfam America, 2001 (Box 466)
    - Paraguay, Assorted Materials, 2008 (Box 466)
    - Paraguay, Country Profile, 2004-2007 (Box 466)
    - Paraguay, USAID, 2006 (Box 466)
    - Peru, Free Trade Agreement, 2007, 2 folders (Box 466)
    - Peru, ILO Convention No. 169 (Box 466)
    - Peru, NGO Law, 2006 (Box 467)
    - Peru, Mining, 2005-2007 (Box 467)
    - Policy, Cash Transfers, 2009, 2 folders (Box 467)
    - PPP, Media Response, 2002 (Box 467)
    - PRODECA, Media Training, 2001 (Box 467)
    - Que Quiere La Gente (Paraguay), 2008 (Box 467)
    - Reyes, Alejandro, "The Geography of Violance", 1998 (Box 467)
    - Robinson, Mary, 2002-2003 (Box 467)
    - Rodrik, Dani, 2001 (Box 467)
    - Rural Development, 2006-2007 (Box 467)
    - Sen, Amartya, 1993-2008 (Box 467)
    - Stiglitz, Joseph, Articles, 2002 (Box 467)
    - SOA, Counter Drug Training, 1996 (Box 467)
    - The International Budget Project, 2002 (Box 467)
    - "The Right to Land" (Box 467)
    - Trade Articles, 2001-2009 (Box 468)
    - Trade, ATPDEA, 2007 (Box 468)
    - Trade Capacity Building, 2002-2007 (Box 468)
    - Trade Policy, Misc., 2007-2009 (Box 468)
    - UCSR, Colombian Refugees, 1999 (Box 468)
    - UN, Economic and Social Council, 1999-2002 (Box 468)
    - UN, Right to Develop, 1986-2002 (Box 468)
    - Unitary Workers Central, Alvaro F. Morales, 2005 (Box 468)
    - USAID, AID Reform, 2 folders (Box 468)
    - US Congress, Free Trade Agreements, 2007 (Box 469)
    - US Counter Narcotics, 1995-2006 (Box 469)
    - US Drug Policy, 2002-2003 (Box 469)
    - US Farm Policy, 2006-2007 (Box 469)
    - US Foreign Assistance, 2008-2009, 2 folders (Box 469)
    - UD Foreign Military Training, 2006 (Box 469)
    - USTR Negotiations, 2003-2004 (Box 469)
    - Venezuela, General (Box 469)
    - Weiner, David, "Pro-Development", 1998 (Box 469)
    - Whistelblower Information (Box 469)
    - WOLA, Colombia (Box 469)
    - WOLA, Economic Issues Program, 1999 (Box 470)
    - WOLA, Human Rights and Development, 2001-2002, 2 folders (Box 470)
    - WOLA, Presentation at Security Event, 2004 (Box 470)
    - WOLA, Security Issues Work Plan, 2006 (Box 470)
    - Woman and Trade, 1999-2002 (Box 470)
    - World Bank, 1999-2002 (Box 470)
    - WTO Conference, Panel Discussion,2003 (Box 470)
    - WTO, Doha Declaration, 2001 (Box 470)
  - General Human Rights
    Contains files of general discussions, conferences, and projects related to the Human Rights Movement in Latin America in the late 1980's and early 1990's.
    - Bob Goldman Seminar, 1991 (Box 472)
    - Dialogo por los Derechos Humanos y La Verdad, 1998 (Box 472)
    - Human Rights NGO's Strategies, 1988 (Box 472)
    - Human Rights Legislation Seminar Series, 1988 (Box 472)
    - International Centre for Human Rights and Democratic Development (ICHRDD) - Research Materials, 1999 (Box 472)
    - Issues in Human Rights, 1990-1991 (Box 472)
    - National Human Rights Institutions, 1995 (Box 472)
    - New Challenges, New Strategies Conference, 1988 (Box 472)
    - WOLA Seminar US Policy and Human Rights, 1988-1989 (Box 472)
  - General Audio Visual
    AV Materials including photos, digital files, training videos, and audio recordings of human rights roundtables and workshops held in El Salvador, Honduras, and Nicaragua. CD's include a 2005 study of the Chixoy Dam, and several digital files, mostly Powerpoint presentations, by Guatemalan/Mayan rights organizations on the disasterous effects of mining operations on Mayan communities.
    - General A/V Material, 2004- 2005, undated, 4 VHS tapes, 7 cassette tapes, 5cds (Box 474)
  - Miscellaneous Files
    - Advocacy Days Packet, 2008 (Box 475)
    - Binder: Foundation Proposals and Reports, 2005-2006; 1 of 10 (Box 475)
    - Binder: WOLA Planning Documents, 2006; 2 of 10 (Box 475)
    - Binder: Just the Facts Project, 2004-2005; 3 of 10 (Box 475)
    - Binder: Southcom, 2001-2006; 4 of 10 (Box 475)
    - Binder: Training and Equipment for Authorities, 2003-2006; 5 of 10 (Box 475)
    - Binder: Military Liaison Elements, 2001-2006; 6 of 10 (Box 475)
    - Binder: OAS "Multidimensional" Security, 2005; 7 of 10 (Box 475)
    - Binder: Rapid Reaction Force, 2005-2006; 8 of 10 (Box 475)
    - Binder: Defense Ministers Conference, 2006; 9 of 10 (Box 475)
    - Binder: ILEA, 2006; 10 of 10 (Box 475)
    - FOIA Documents Related to Central America Free Trade Agreement, 2005; 1 of 3 (Box 475)
    - FOIA Documents Related to Central America Free Trade Agreement, 2005; 2 of 3 (Box 475)
    - FOIA Documents Related to Central America Free Trade Agreement, 2005; 3 of 3 (Box 475)
    - WOLA Information Packet, 1997 (Box 475)
    - IHRLG - Derechos Humanos y la OEA, 1999-2000 (Box 475)
    - US Southern Documents, 1997 (Box 476)
    - South Com Documents, 1998 (Box 476)
    - Southcom Posture Statement, 1999 (Box 476)
    - US Southcom Joint Combined Exchange Training (JCET), 1999-2000 (Box 476)
    - Southcom Posture Statement, 2000 (Box 476)